# SURENDRA KUMAR CHUNDURI

Address Hyderabad, 500018

**Phone** +91 850 044 9900

E-mail skumar.chunduri@skchunduri.me

- Result oriented, Self-Starter Business Architect with 10+years of Business-Critical Project Handling
  Experience in roles including Sr. Business Analyst, Product Owner, Technical Business Analyst following
  Agile Methodology
- Business Analysis expertise in leading the domains such as- Business Process Management (BPM),
   Product Development, Digital Transformation, Continuous Process Improvement, Business Process
   Automation, Business Continuity and End User Technology
- Experience in leading Discovery Session involving all stake holders and then developing the features and Epics related to the program/project.
- Proficient in documenting business processes, process flows, data flows, use cases.
- Experience in breaking and converting the user requirements in to deliverables, epics and user stories for proper requirement elaboration, management and maintenance.
- Experience in conducting DCO sessions and capturing case workflows in Pega.
- Experience in reviewing, validating proposed application design and ensure scalability of design.
- Demonstrative Scrum Master with background in communicating effectively with and leading highperformance teams.
- Proven track record of transforming specific business goals related to growth and efficiency improvements into new system designs.

### **Skills**

3KIII3		
	Business analysis	Advanced
	Quality assurance	Upper intermediate
	Business Intelligence Reporting	Intermediate
	Requirement Engineering	Upper intermediate
	User Stories	Upper intermediate
Software		
	Axure RP8	Upper intermediate

PEGA	Intermediate
Cognos	Intermediate
Qlikview	Intermediate
Databases	Intermediate
UI Path	Elementary
Automation Anywhere	Elementary
HP ALM	Intermediate

# **Work History**

## 2022-03 - 2023-12 **Pega Lead Business Architect**

Instellars Global Consulting Private Limited, Hyderabad

- Support development of Process descriptions, functional requirements and specifications during facilitated workshops and meetings with business users and stakeholders.
- Gap Analysis -Identify Pain Areas and required features to improve process efficiency and user experience.
- Utilized creative problem-solving skills to overcome technical challenges in sales process.
- Drafting Use cases and user stories and Responsible for obtaining sign-off
- Worked closely with sales team on understanding customer requirements, promoting products and delivering sales support.
- Analyze and document AS-Is Process using workflows, , interface diagrams.
- Responded to specific customer requests, including RFP responses and industryspecific solutions.
- Collaborating with stakeholders and IT teams. Conducting reviews and Obtaining Sign-offs.
- Capture Requirements, Specifications and use cases in DCO and map them to appropriate rules.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.
- Review and certify test scenarios for coverage
- Validate Feasibility of new functions/ Features
- Assist Architects in creating proposed work flow
- Tested and aided design on API's for system integration using API tools like Postman.

• Iterative demonstration of applications in development for feedbacks and time course correction and also to prep UAT users.

### 2022-12 - Current Lead Business Architect

LTIMindtree, Hyderabad

- Support the development of Process descriptions, functional requirements and specifications during facilitated workshops and meetings with the business users and stakeholders
- Led brainstorming sessions to outline new features and address system faults in subsequent update
- Capture Requirements, Specifications and use cases in DCO and map them to the appropriate rules.
- Mapped functional client requirements to Pega software by translating functionality into complex user stories
- Drafting Use cases and user stories and Responsible for obtaining sign-off
- Collaborating with stakeholders and IT teams. Conducting reviews and Obtaining Sign-offs
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.
- Validate Feasibility of new functions/ Features
- Assist Architects in creating the proposed work flow
- Tested and aided the design on API's for system integration using API tools like Postman.
- Defect-Management -Validate, Triage, verify and close
- Shepherded change requests through process with appropriate documentation, schedule and cost oversight and facilitated request approval.
- Supported end-to-end user acceptance testing for developed products to support client satisfaction and address complaints
- Iterative demonstration of applications in development for feedbacks and time course correction and also to prep UAT users.

# 2021-03 - 2022-03 Pega Lead Business Architect

Tech Mahindra Limited, Hyderabad

- Focused on building critical features up front in order to identify constraints and technical challenges.
- Gap Analysis -Identify Pain Areas and required features to improve process efficiency and user experience.
- Collaborating with stakeholders and IT teams. Conducting reviews and Obtaining Sign-offs.
- Capture Requirements, Specifications and use cases in DCO and map them to appropriate rules.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.
- Altered or reengineered process to automate or improve process inefficiencies
- Directed and led documentation of business requirements, functional specifications and other client deliverables

- Validate Feasibility of new functions/ Features
- Assist Architects in creating proposed work flow
- Tested and aided design on API's for system integration using API tools like Postman.
- Certify application for progress to system testing and UAT testing
- Defect-Management -Validate, Triage, verify and close
- Responsible UAT and Certifying application for promoting it to production

#### 2021-02 - 2021-03

## Pega Lead Business Architect

High Noon Consulting Private Limited (Deloitte consulting Private Limited), Hyderabad

- Work in High Demand Environment Perform role of Business Architect for development streams.
- Support development of Process descriptions, functional requirements and specifications during facilitated workshops and meetings with business users and stakeholders.
- Gap Analysis -Identify Pain Areas and required features to improve process efficiency and user experience.
- Drafting Use cases and user stories and Responsible for obtaining sign-off
- Analyze and document AS-Is Process using workflows, Swimlanes, interface diagrams.
- Collaborating with stakeholders and IT teams. Conducting reviews and Obtaining Sign-offs.
- Capture Requirements, Specifications and use cases in DCO and map them to appropriate rules.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.
- Review and certify test scenarios for coverage
- Validate Feasibility of new functions/ Features
- Assist Architects in creating proposed work flow
- Tested and aided design on API's for system integration using API tools like Postman.
- Certify application for progress to system testing and UAT testing
- Defect-Management -Validate, Triage, verify and close
- Co-ordinate UAT
- Iterative demonstration of applications in development for feedbacks and time course correction and also to prep UAT users.

#### 2020-01 - 2021-02

# Pega Lead Business Architect

Eclat Prime Digital Private Limited (Deloitte Consulting Private Limited), Hyderabad

- Work in High Demand Environment Perform role of Business Architect for Parallel development streams.
- Support the development of Process descriptions, functional requirements and specifications during facilitated workshops and meetings with the business users and stakeholders.

- Gap Analysis -Identify Pain Areas and required features to improve process efficiency and user experience.
- Drafting Use cases and user stories and Responsible for obtaining sign-off
- Analyze and document AS-Is Process using workflows, Swimlanes, interface diagrams.
- Collaborating with stakeholders and IT teams. Conducting reviews and Obtaining Sign-offs.
- Capture Requirements, Specifications and use cases in DCO and map them to the appropriate rules.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.
- Review and certify test scenarios for coverage
- Validate Feasibility of new functions/ Features
- Assist Architects in creating the proposed work flow
- Tested and aided the design on API's for system integration using API tools like Postman.
- Certify application for progress to system testing and UAT testing
- Defect-Management -Validate, Triage, verify and close
- Co-ordinate UAT
- Iterative demonstration of applications in development for feedbacks and time course correction and also to prep UAT users.

#### 2017-12 - 2020-01

### **Product Owner/Pega Business Architect**

E-Pragati Authority, Government Of Andhra Pradesh, Vijayawada

- Managed product backlog and supported SCRUM framework for Biweekly sprint releases.
- Devised, deployed and monitored processes to boost long-term business success and increase revenue levels by 50% and service delivery times reduced by 90.
- Oversaw entire product deployments from vision and creation to rollout and delivery.
- Focused on building critical features up front in order to identify constraints and technical challenges.
- Gap Analysis -Identify Pain Areas and required features to improve process efficiency and user experience.
- Drafting Use cases and user stories and Responsible for obtaining sign-off
- Analyze and document AS-Is Process using workflows, Swimlanes, interface diagrams.
- Collaborating with stakeholders and IT teams. Conducting reviews and Obtaining Sign-offs.
- Capture Requirements, Specifications and use cases in DCO and map them to the appropriate rules.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and propose options to rectify operational inefficiencies.
- Review and certify test scenarios for coverage
- Validate Feasibility of new functions/ Features

- Assist Architects in creating the proposed work flow
- Tested and aided the design on API's for system integration using API tools like Postman.
- Certify application for progress to system testing and UAT testing
- Defect-Management -Validate, Triage, verify and close
- Responsible UAT and Certifying the application for promoting it to production.

# 2017-05 - 2017-12 **Technical Business Analyst**

Adya Smart, Hyderabad

- Oversaw entire product deployments from vision and creation to rollout and delivery.
- Manage the feature backlog and co-ordinate the inputs form the architecture team and business to estimate, prioritize and scope items in each iterative phase.
- Managed implementation of new features by outlining plans and specifications such as how, where and when each component would work.
- Created Functional Specs, User Stories, Use- cases, Process flows and Future State mock-ups to product requirements deliverables for Smart Energy Management systems
- Researched competitors to build report of rising trends in Smart Metering markets.
- Worked with business leaders to understand business strategy and later influence how the strategy would drive planned systems/ Process/Process/Organizational Capabilities.
- Provided support to the program managers by creating sound Business cases, including business, technical and financial feasibility assessment.
- Evaluated and adopted new technologies to address changing industry needs.
- Established compatibility with third party software products by developing program for modification and integration.
- With the implementation of new Energy Management systems, the client business has reduced the energy losses by 50% and revenue got increased by 25%.

# 2015-06 - 2016-10 Business Systems Analyst

Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd, AGCO, Hyderabad

- Collected, defined and analyzed business requirements.
- Formulated and designed computer systems using data modeling, information engineering and structured analysis.
- Assessed strategic implications of business intelligence data for Purchasing and Projects area.
- Reviewed files, records and other documents to obtain business information and key data in order to respond to development requests.
- Designing and producing detailed use cases, business process models and screen flow diagrams.
- Prepared and delivered targeted systems training for business personnel.

• With Implementation of the new system, the North America Purchasing Team approval times has got reduced by 90% and the availability got increased by 99.99%.

### 2015-01 - 2015-05 **Consultant**

Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd, JP Morgan, Hyderabad

- Assessed, defined and document scope of projects.
- Mapped process activities to identify shortfalls and identify options to rectify operational inefficiencies.
- Documented business processes and analyzed procedures to align with changing business needs.
- Performed system analysis, documentation, testing, implementation and user support for platform transitions.
- Evaluated consistency and importance of different business intelligence data against needs to determine optimal courses of action.
- With new Systems in place, JP Morgan could be able to complete assessment can be completed with in 7 days to 30 days before awarding contracts.

# 2013-01 - 2014-05 Product Owner/Business Analyst

Kishore Technolgies Pvt Ltd, 123 Comms LTD, Peterborough, UK

- Owned and prioritized product backlog.
- Managed implementation of new features by outlining plans and specifications such as how, where and when each component would work.
- Collected and reviewed engineering data to assess needs and recommend solutions.
- Investigated processes to develop maps and determine optimal improvement approaches.
- First point of Contact to Support Team regarding legacy applications.

# 2011-09 - 2012-12 Business Systems Analyst

Kishore Technolgies Pvt Ltd, AB Foods PLC, Peterborough, UK

- Derived conceptual designs from business objectives to deliver software and applications according to specifications for usability, performance and functionality.
- Collected, analysed and defined business requirements.
- Boosted information sharing by enhancing interfaces between computer systems.
- Facilitating workshops with key business stakeholders and dealers to gather and document high level and detailed dealer/customer journey activities.
- Synthesised current business intelligence data to produce reports and polished presentations highlighting findings and recommending changes.
- Trained business personnel in use of systems.

#### Education

2010-09 - 2011-11	Master of Science: International Business Management, Marketing Heriot- Watt University - Edinburgh, Scotland
2005-09 - 2009-05	B. Tech: Computer Science and Engineering Institute of Aeronautical Engineering - Hyderabad, TG
Certifications	

2019-11	Certified Scrum Product Owner
2019-05	Certified Pega Business Architect
2022-10	The Open Group Architecture Framework (TOGAF) 9.2 Certified
2023-02	Safe Agilest

2019-11 Certified Scrum Master